<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-23T19:57:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Geoff Whiting</title><subtitle>This is the home of Geoff Whiting, a Washington DC writer and content marketer.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Business Networking 101: Understanding And Selecting The Right Network To Satisfy Team And Customer Demands In Today’s Fast-Paced World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/business-networking-101-understanding-and-selecting-the-right-network-to-satisfy-team-and-customer-demands-in-today-s-fast-paced-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Business Networking 101: Understanding And Selecting The Right Network To Satisfy Team And Customer Demands In Today's Fast-Paced World" /><published>2020-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/business-networking-101-understanding-and-selecting-the-right-network-to-satisfy-team-and-customer-demands-in-today-s-fast-paced-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/business-networking-101-understanding-and-selecting-the-right-network-to-satisfy-team-and-customer-demands-in-today-s-fast-paced-world/">&lt;p&gt;Tens of billions of devices are connected to the internet right at this moment, and each depends on a strong network to operate correctly. Businesses account for a majority of these devices, and their customers are becoming the most demanding segment on the planet when it comes to network access and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put together this paper for Hudson Fiber Network COO Keith Muller to talk about building the right network.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><summary type="html">Tens of billions of devices are connected to the internet right at this moment, and each depends on a strong network to operate correctly. Businesses account for a majority of these devices, and their customers are becoming the most demanding segment on the planet when it comes to network access and reliability.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/red-lights-in-line-on-black-surface-158826.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Analytics Is Shaping HR’s Role In Business</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-analytics-is-shaping-hr-s-role-in-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Analytics Is Shaping HR's Role In Business" /><published>2020-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-analytics-is-shaping-hr-s-role-in-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-analytics-is-shaping-hr-s-role-in-business/">&lt;p&gt;Data analytics in Human Resources is quickly becoming a new area of innovation and focus because of the insights it can provide around workforce management. Workforce analytics has emerged as the key avenue for HR to become a proactive force for managing human capital and strengthen business strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whitepaper reviews the state of HR analytics and was a successful promotional that drove a significant increase in attendance to the HR Analytics Summit West 2015 conference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><summary type="html">Data analytics in Human Resources is quickly becoming a new area of innovation and focus because of the insights it can provide around workforce management. Workforce analytics has emerged as the key avenue for HR to become a proactive force for managing human capital and strengthen business strategies.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/blue-tree-painting-2397989.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Get A Complete Cloud WMS Buyers’ Guide On EXPLOREWMS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/get-a-complete-cloud-wms-buyers-guide-on-explorewms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Get A Complete Cloud WMS Buyers' Guide On EXPLOREWMS" /><published>2020-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/get-a-complete-cloud-wms-buyers-guide-on-explorewms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/get-a-complete-cloud-wms-buyers-guide-on-explorewms/">&lt;p&gt;Every aspect of our daily lives has moved to the cloud, and your warehouse’s functionality is following the same track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You now can turn all your daily activities to cloud-based services and solutions, hopefully helping you move faster and have a more efficient operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real-time data is a powerhouse, and the right tool can unlock it. However, it can be a little tricky picking the right cloud warehouse management system that will help you achieve the improvements and success that are possible with this new type of WMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://explorewms.com/cloud-wms-buyers-guide.html&quot;&gt;I put together a comprehensive cloud WMS purchase guide for the ExploreWMS brand. You can find it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:&lt;a href=&quot;https://explorewms.com/cloud-wms-buyers-guide.html&quot; title=&quot;https://explorewms.com/cloud-wms-buyers-guide.html&quot;&gt;https://explorewms.com/cloud-wms-buyers-guide.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><summary type="html">Every aspect of our daily lives has moved to the cloud, and your warehouse’s functionality is following the same track.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/architecture-buildings-business-city-325185.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Executive Lessons on Modern Text Analytics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/executive-lessons-on-modern-text-analytics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Executive Lessons on Modern Text Analytics" /><published>2020-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/executive-lessons-on-modern-text-analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/executive-lessons-on-modern-text-analytics/">&lt;p&gt;Unstructured data may be the most prevalent form of information on the planet. It exists in our e-mails, surveys, social media accounts, call center logs and even reports like this. Not only is between 60% and 80% of corporate data unstructured, but the way people communicate is predominantly unstructured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whitepaper looks at the power of text analytics to understand unstructured data.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><summary type="html">Unstructured data may be the most prevalent form of information on the planet. It exists in our e-mails, surveys, social media accounts, call center logs and even reports like this. Not only is between 60% and 80% of corporate data unstructured, but the way people communicate is predominantly unstructured.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/woman-using-ipad-2343480.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Turn Hurdles Into Opportunities By Understanding The RPA Challenges Facing SMBS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/turn-hurdles-into-opportunities-by-understanding-the-rpa-challenges-facing-smbs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Turn Hurdles Into Opportunities By Understanding The RPA Challenges Facing SMBS" /><published>2020-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/turn-hurdles-into-opportunities-by-understanding-the-rpa-challenges-facing-smbs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/turn-hurdles-into-opportunities-by-understanding-the-rpa-challenges-facing-smbs/">&lt;p&gt;Enterprises are experts at gaining media attention when it comes to any new, exciting system or process, but the largest impact of business-positive technologies is often felt by small and mid-sized firms. The latest buzz to live in the big business space is Robotic Process Automation (RPA), but it’s time we push it squarely into the SMB realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small businesses face consistent time and workforce crunches, struggling to keep up with the balance of growth and new hires alongside maintaining customer relationships and completing all the daily tasks required to run a business. Working those 10+ hours a day, unfortunately, brings in a lot of tired mornings and bleary-eyed nights, where human error can slip in quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RPA helps to address those manual-error concerns by using boys to perform repetitive tasks on the UIs that people work with regularly. This can be your billing or IT systems with very clear tools that work on strict rules and structured data, though it can also be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workfusion.com/robotic-process-automation-rpa?utm_source=other&amp;amp;utm_medium=business2community&amp;amp;utm_name=geoff-whiting&amp;amp;utm_content=rpa&amp;amp;utm_term=turn-hurdles-into-opportunities-by-understanding-the-rpa-challenges-facing-smbs&quot;&gt;combined with cognitive automation and AI&lt;/a&gt; in more complex scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-piece-was-posted-originally-on-business-2-community-read-more-here&quot;&gt;MY PIECE WAS POSTED ORIGINALLY ON BUSINESS 2 COMMUNITY: READ MORE &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.business2community.com/business-intelligence/turn-hurdles-opportunities-understanding-rpa-challenges-facing-smbs-02042029&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name>Geoff</name></author><summary type="html">Enterprises are experts at gaining media attention when it comes to any new, exciting system or process, but the largest impact of business-positive technologies is often felt by small and mid-sized firms. The latest buzz to live in the big business space is Robotic Process Automation (RPA), but it’s time we push it squarely into the SMB realm.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/grayscale-photography-of-chairs-in-an-auditorium-2305084.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Telegram Open Network (TON) White Paper</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/telegram-open-network-ton-white-paper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Telegram Open Network (TON) White Paper" /><published>2020-01-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/telegram-open-network-ton-white-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/telegram-open-network-ton-white-paper/">&lt;p&gt;I provided English-language edits as well as content direction and strategy for the media-focused white-paper for Telegram’s ICO and pre-ICO efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company raised $1.7 billion in pre-ICO sales in March 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><summary type="html">I provided English-language edits as well as content direction and strategy for the media-focused white-paper for Telegram’s ICO and pre-ICO efforts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/telegram.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Maximising Upsells Through Personalisation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/maximising-upsells-through-personalisation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maximising Upsells Through Personalisation" /><published>2020-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/maximising-upsells-through-personalisation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/maximising-upsells-through-personalisation/">&lt;p&gt;Personalizing offers for each individual client has become a key differentiator among sites and services. Today’s carriers and online travel agencies need to have a system in place to take full advantage of the data they’re already collecting for both the initial sale and potential up- or cross-sells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whitepaper was created for EyeforTravel’s Business Intelligence unit to help frame the personalization discussion for the modern travel customer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><summary type="html">Personalizing offers for each individual client has become a key differentiator among sites and services. Today’s carriers and online travel agencies need to have a system in place to take full advantage of the data they’re already collecting for both the initial sale and potential up- or cross-sells.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/blue-abstract-painting-1568607.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Three Lessons For Meaningful Brand Storytelling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three Lessons For Meaningful Brand Storytelling" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/">&lt;p&gt;Kings of coffee shops, queens of the stage, and jokers everywhere are keepers of an often undervalued business skill: storytelling. They use storytelling to keep their audience engaged and coming back for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cultural love of “Mad Men” has shown us that the ability to create a compelling story allows any brand to sell a product, but storytelling’s power doesn’t stop there. It works just as well within your organization to push for any new idea. Spinning an engaging story allows you to turn a bland fact or piece of information into an idea, and then guide your audience to a desired conclusion. Your fact is now their truth and it’s not just limited to a sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storytelling even can be more persuasive than purely logical arguments, according to studies like &lt;a href=&quot;this one from Ohio State University&quot;&gt;this one from Ohio State University&lt;/a&gt;. This is true even in data-centric industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my work with major analytics companies and divisions, storytelling has even emerged as a key differentiator that helps a candidate get hired. These branches need a storyteller who can weave complex information into a narrative that quickly presents insights to executive leadership. A good storyteller translates into better financial support, which in turn can yield more insightful business intelligence and a stronger return on investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news for everyone is that telling an engaging story gets easy when you put the right pieces into place. Whether you’re deep in data or want a blog that gets customers to make a purchase, here are three important considerations that can turn your tales into gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-with-your-lesson&quot;&gt;Start With Your Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you begin crafting a story, decide what you want someone to understand and believe at the end. Keep your audience in mind and make your lesson important to the audience by framing it in something they desire. For businesses, this often is positioning a product or service as a best solution to a problem to make the customer’s day better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-a-conflict&quot;&gt;Find a Conflict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories that survive the test of time tend to present a great conflict with someone the reader can root for –someone the audience identifies with and feels interchangeable with. Understandable Conflicts or challenges makes your story compelling. Improve your business storytelling by establishing a clear line from the problem to its solution via your takeaway. Mix in a few finer details to keep your story from feeling too much like a pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limit-your-background-explanation&quot;&gt;Limit Your Background Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help your story engage with a wider audience by making the “why” behind the problem broad. It’s important to explain the root cause, but be careful of description that can limit your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s assume you’re selling a product that can be used anytime of the year. Making a “2015 Spring Cleaning” blog post gives you an easy theme to work with to tout your benefits. Unfortunately, the post’s perceived usefulness can end once summer arrives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply removing references to 2015 can extend your content’s usefulness to the following spring. That’s an extra year (at least) just by removing the date from your headline. To extend it even further, you can broaden the theme to general cleaning to expand it from a 3-month window to any time of the year. If you like the Spring Cleaning theme, use it in your social media promotions. It harnesses the immediacy of social networks, but gives the heart of your story an evergreen approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining these three simple lessons can give you a better story and help you achieve goals from improved traffic and conversions to convincing your boss to fund your project, department, or ambition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-lagniappe-lesson&quot;&gt;THE LAGNIAPPE LESSON&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skip any part you find boring. Whether you’re presenting to a crowd, writing on a blog or tweeting out to the world, slow parts ruin stories. Cherry-pick your facts and descriptions to create quick, engaging content. It gets your audience to your takeaway faster and they’ll enjoy the experience that much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was cross posted on LinkedIn here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><category term="summer" /><summary type="html">Kings of coffee shops, queens of the stage, and jokers everywhere are keepers of an often undervalued business skill: storytelling. They use storytelling to keep their audience engaged and coming back for more.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/16.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Does Your Business Want AI or RPA?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first-mass-produced/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does Your Business Want AI or RPA?" /><published>2019-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first-mass-produced</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first-mass-produced/">&lt;p&gt;Business process automation is a multi-billion-dollar industry where new services crop up every day under the “automation” heading. Nearly 20% of U.S. enterprises use some form of this automation, and almost all refer to it as AI, but that’s leading some to complain that they aren’t getting access to all the miracles promised by smarter services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the boom in offerings hasn’t always come with an equally large outpouring of explanations about the differences in AI, machine learning, process automation, and much more. Two big camps are fighting for business investment right now — AI and RPA — so I thought it might be good to share a little bit about what sets the two apart and how you can make a quick determination about what your business needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that discovering the difference will make it easier to set expectations and budgets when you go for the all-important executive buy-in for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read my entire piece on Business2Community &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.business2community.com/business-intelligence/business-want-ai-rpa-02045980&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>geoff</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Business process automation is a multi-billion-dollar industry where new services crop up every day under the “automation” heading. Nearly 20% of U.S. enterprises use some form of this automation, and almost all refer to it as AI, but that’s leading some to complain that they aren’t getting access to all the miracles promised by smarter services.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/silhouette-of-person-holding-glass-mason-jar-1274260.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Accumulated experience of social living</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/acumulated-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accumulated experience of social living" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/acumulated-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/acumulated-experience/">&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Geoff</name></author><summary type="html">The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/15.jpg" /></entry></feed>